Guide to the Ross Lee Baker papers, 1910-1947.
Baker, Ross Lee papers, 1910-1947.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ross Lee Baker papers, 1910-1947
3629
Ross Lee Baker, 1884-1975
3 cubic ft.
Letters, legal records, and news clippings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Clippings, engineering reports, letters, financial records, legal records, travel notes, and articles of Ross L. Baker.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Ross L. Baker was an inventor and an engineer. He organized R. L. Baker and Co. Engineers, a firm of consulting engineers in New York City. Cornell University Class of 1907.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Clippings, engineering reports, letters, financial records, legal records, travel notes, and articles of Ross L. Baker
SUBJECTS
Names:
Baker, Ross Lee, 1884-1975.; R.L. Baker and Co. Engineers.
Subjects:
Mechanical engineering.; Engineers--New York (State)--New York.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Materials
Box 1
Series II. Correspondence
Box 1
Series III. Professional Papers
Boxes 1-3
Series IV. Personal Records
Boxes 3-4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Materials
  - Affidavit of Birth, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Greenwood Union School Commencement Recital programs, 1901-1902 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Competitive exams for Cornell University scholarships, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Who's Who in Engineering forms, 1921-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Engineering License Application, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Certificate to Practice Engineering, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Alvorez, Carolee (cousin), 1901 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baker, A. W. (father), 1916-1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Baker, (mother), 1912-1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baker, Kelts C. (brother), 1912-1941 (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
  - Baker, Mrs. Kelts (Gertrude), 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Baker, Noyes A. (uncle), 1907-1912 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Buchanan, G. W., 1910 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bump, Milan Reynard, 1913, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Burger, R. E., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - C., Marybell, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Chilcote, S. S. C., 1916 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clifford, George H., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cobb, Louise K., 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Davis, Edgar B., 1923-1933 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Doherty, Henry L., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Fisk, Eugene Lyman, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gaines, G. N., 1918 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Gravelle, J. Silas, 1912-1916 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - H., M. M., 1918 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Haylor, Geo. E., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - House, Mansfield F., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Hutchinson, F. L., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Jolles, Jan, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - [Kellogg], Will, 1909, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Kennedy, T. O., 1923-1930 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Kitchin, Edgar M., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Kurtz, Ford, 1908-1914 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Latham, J. C., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Leonard, John W. Corporation, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Lincoln, C. S., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Lindsay, Anna J., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Mallory, Marie, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - McAdoo, Malcolm R., 1915 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - McKenzie, F. W., 1908-1911 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - McSweeny, Florence C., 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Norris, Herriette B, 1912-1916 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Olds, Thomas H., 1909 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Orr, J. D., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Parshall, Blanch M., 1915 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Pauling, Mildred, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Pratt, Florence M., 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Satterlee, W. A., 1910 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Schwenke, Gertrude D., 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Schwenke, Nelle, 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Scott, Eva, 1913-1923 (Box 1, Folder 54-60)
  - Scott, Holton H., 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Sharpe, Dr., 1918 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Sheldon, M. C., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Turner, Lester W., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Watson, Katherine, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Constance, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Mary, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - May, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Pitt, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence: Misc. historical, 191-1941 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence: RB New York Office, pre-1925 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence: JW New York Office, pre-1925 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - A. Project Correspondence
    - Hydro Power: Condensing Water Experiments, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Public utilities (brokerage): Brush Electric Co., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Public utilities (brokerage): Durham vs. Duke power, 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Public utilities (brokerage): Middletown, Conn., 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Public utilities (brokerage): New England (S. W. Plate), 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Public utilities (operation), 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Series III. Professional Papers
  - A. Reports and Documents
    - Examination forms, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Engineering Reports: Sibley College reports, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Distribution Reports: Electric Engineering audit, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Electric Distribution: Method of Estimating Lost Current in Electric Distribution, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Electric Distribution: Methods of Limiting Lost Energy in Electric Distribution, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Electric RR Report Model, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Gas Distribution System, Ideal, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Electrical Distribution: Report for Electrical Distribution Department of Doherty Operating Co., 1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - N.E.L.A. Report on the Secondary Network and Banking of Transformers, 1915, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Report forms and models: Transmission Line, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Transmission Line Specifications, 1913-1923 (Box 2, Folder 4-8)
    - Boulder, Colorado: water supply, 1916-1921 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Boulder and Orodell, Colorado: water supply, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Denver Colorado: water supply, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Golden, Colorado: Jefferson County Power and Light Company, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Marshall and Eldorado Springs, Colorado: water records, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Hutchinson, Kansas: promotional brochure, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hutchinson, Kansas: engineer's report, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Salina, Kansas: engineer's report, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Sterling and Lyons, Kansas: summary of engineer's report, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Minnesota Gas and Electric Company: auditor's report, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Boonville, Missouri: engineer's report, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - California, Missouri: engineer's report, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Joplin, Missouri: report on proposed distribution system, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Moberly (Mo.) Light & Power Co.: engineer's report, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Trenton (Mo.) Gas & Electric Co.: engineer's report, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Warrensburg, Missouri: engineer's report, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Hudson & Manhattan Company (railroad) (New York), 1913 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Long Island Electric Railway Company & New York & Long Island Traction Company: preliminary report, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - New York & Queens Railway Co., N. Y. & Long Island Traction Co., Long Island Electric Railway Co., Montauk Water Co., 1915 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - New York & North Jersey Rapid Transit Company: estimate of gross earnings, engineer's report, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Tuckaseegee Hydraulic project, North Carolina: estimate, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Auglaize Power Company, Defiance, Ohio: summary of engineers' report, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Lima Territory, Ohio: engineer's estimate on power supply, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Lima, Ohio: business estimate on transmission project and property purchase, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Lorain, Ohio: engineer's report on The Citizens Gas & Electric Company, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Massillon, Ohio: photos, letter, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Stark County, Ohio: (electric) engineering report, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Parr Shoals, Columbia, S. C.: earnings & hydro electric development reports, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Kingsport, Tenn.: summary of field notes, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Flat Shoals (N.C./Tenn.): Watauga River Project, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Corsicana, Texas: engineer's reports, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - B. Publications
  - 1. Periodicals
    - Doherty News, 1916-1923 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Doherty Daily News, 1915-1919 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Cities Service Company: two reports, 1919, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Publications Misc.: public corporation, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Publications Misc.: interconnections between power systems, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Publications Misc.: "Results for Toledo", 1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Climatological data, notes, 1910-1920 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Electric Distribution Bulletin, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - N.E.L.A. (National Electrical Light Association): Accident Prevention Course for Linemen, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - N.E.L.A.: Accident Prevention Committee reports, 1921-1924 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - N.E.L.A.: Design and Construction of Distribution Systems, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - N.E.L.A.: Inductive Coordination Committee report, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - N.E.L.A.: Inductive Interference Committee report, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - N.E.L.A.: Specifications for Overhead Construction Materials, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - N.E.L.A.: Rate Reduction In the Last Three Years, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - N.E.L.A.: Valuation for Rate Making Purposes, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous N.E.L.A. Publications, 1917-1924 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 2. Published Maps
    - Montgomery, Alabama, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - California: three maps, 1923-1928 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Colorado: ten maps, 1904-1922, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Maryland, District of Columbia, Virginia, West Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - New York and North Jersey (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Ohio: four maps, 1915-1919, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Europe, Germany, 1917, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series IV. Personal Records
  - A. Business
    - Invention: electrical circuit protector, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Inventions: boxing glove improvement, miscellany, 1912-1929 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Patents, miscellaneous, 1911-1919 (Box 3, Folder 16-20)
    - Projects: notes, miscellany, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Valuation and Rate making for Public Utilities: notes, miscellany, 1917-1923 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - B. Non-Business
    - Identification: passport, various documents and cards, 1902-1929 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Accounts, 1902-1921 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
    - Bank accounts, 1907-1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous receipts, 1912-1974 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Architecture, 1929-1939 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Art, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Athletics: Boxing, 1908-1914 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - History: World War, 1914-1918, 1917-1919 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Insurance, 1939-1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Literature (some poetry), 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Mechanics & Physics, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous: writings, notes, personnel lists, etc., 1919-1944 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Real Estate: Ithaca, 1956-1970 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Travel (mostly U.S.): notes, miscellany, 1913-1929 (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
    - Family Photographs, 1913, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Pins, ribbon, 1912, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Wills, 1963, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - General Power of Attorney, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Patent, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - California maps (Yosemite), 1920, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 4)